字幕翻译/压制：旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/hsul-GE4XiA
原视频发布日期：20190925
原作者名：Everyday Astronaut
- Hi it's me, Tim Dodd the Everyday Astronaut.
- 嗨 我是Tim Dodd 每日宇航员
Starship更新指的是2019年9月28日的Starship更新发布会
We're less than a week away from this year's Starship update from Elon Musk,
离今年马一龙的Starship更新还差不到一周了
and before the party gets started,
在开会之前
we're already catching some major changes happening before our eyes.
我们已经发现了一些巨大的变化
That's because as we speak SpaceX is building the Mark 1 Starship prototype,
这是因为SpaceX正在建造Starship的原型机Starship一号机
right there in Boca Chica where the presentation will be held on September 28th.
也就是9月28日将会在博卡奇卡进行报告的地方
And of course, because it's being built out in a field in public,
当然因为它是公开地建造的
we're seeing some major updates to the hardware.
我们正看到硬件上的一些重大更新
The most obvious change is the fact
最明显的变化是
that the Starship has only two finney flappy air-brakey things now instead of three,
Starship只会有两个可以折叠的翼状气动阻力板一样的东西而不是三个
and the previous version touted just a year ago at the Dear Moon event
而仅仅一年前在 亲爱的月球 大会中推销的版本
showed Starship sporting three fins that were also its landing legs.
显示Starship是有三个既是后方翼面也是着陆腿的装置
So now that we're seeing it only has two,
而现在我们只看到了两个
the question has come up, and it's come up a lot.
问题来了
Why, why just two?
为啥只有两个
So today, we're gonna do a really quick rundown on why two might be better than three,
那么今天 我们要快速讲解一下为什么两个会比三个好
show you some potential problems that three fins had,
展示一些三个翼面存在的问题
and then we'll show you exactly how they'll control the re-entry and landing with just two rear fins.
然后我会告诉你他们是如何只使用两个后方翼面来控制再入和着陆的
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧
(rousing music)
(扶正祛邪音乐)
- [Mission Control] Three, two, one,
-  [任务控制]三 二 一
and liftoff!
和升空
(upbeat music)
(欢快的音乐)
- [Neil] That's one small step for man.
-  [尼尔]这是对人类的一小步
- [Mission Control] That's Houston contact for the test one.
-  [任务控制]这是休斯敦和一号测试的通信
- Okay, first things first.
- 好吧 首先
I think it'd be fun to do a quick rundown here on this fun little bit of engineering
得总结下这个这个有趣的工程设计
while we get ready for the event on the 28th,
在准备参加9月28日的大会之前
so, when it gets revealed, we can be like, "Ah, yeah."
这样 当它公开的时候 我们可以如此说 果然没错
And since I've been way too busy now for over two months,
而且因为我最近两个多月都特别忙
气尖引擎那一期已经甩锅给了 @长五遥三没有鸽
working on what's become literally a documentary on the aerospike engine,
忙着做几乎快变成纪录片的气尖引擎的视频
I figured I'd better crank out a nice easy video here in the meantime.
我最好在这时做个又好又短的视频
Okay, so now before we get going,
在我们继续之前
I wanted to remind you these are not wings.
我想提醒你这些不是机翼
They are really just giant air brakes,
它们只是巨型的气动阻力板
or body flaps, as Elon once called them.
或者是马斯克一直说的体襟翼
Ew. (laughing)
呃  (笑)
They are perpendicular to the airstream and not parallel,
它们垂直而非平行于气流
but we'll call them fins or flaps interchangeably in this video.
但在这个视频里我们会称之为翼面或者襟翼
And another note. We're gonna use Kerbal Space Program here in this video.
另外一个注意 这个视频里会出现坎巴拉太空计划(KSP)
And if you're triggered by a game, settle down, settle down.
如果你被游戏震惊到了 冷静下
We're gonna use Kerbal to illustrate some of the problems and demonstrate some of the solutions,
我们会利用KSP来展示和解决一些问题
but we're doing this knowing this isn't an engineering tool for validations or argument sake.
但并不是用此来当作工程学上的验证或者调参的工具
Regardless, it's still a great demonstrator of the basic physics,
无论如何 它仍然是只是基本物理学的演示
and it definitely helps visualize some of the challenges involved.
它肯定有助于可视化一些问题
Okay, so let's start off with the obvious reason of why there's now two fins instead of three.
首先讲讲用两个后方翼面而不是三个的主要原因
Wait, according to Elon Musk,
等下 根据马一龙说的
"Current analysis, which I'm not fully bought into,"
我并不完全赞同当前的分析
"suggests that two rear fins with separate airframe-mounted legs will be lighter,"
这个分析说两个后方翼面加上另外附在机身上的支腿(的方案)会更轻
"so this is the plan for Mark 1 and Mark 2."
所以这就是1号机和2号机的方案了
So it sounds like there may be some internal debate here on what's lighter,
那么听起来内部曾经发生过哪种方案更轻的争论
and for now, two fins seems to have won out.
到目前为止 两个后方翼面的方案胜出了
But part of me thinks that Elon really loved the old-school look of the three fins at the rear.
但我总觉得马一龙喜欢那种三后方翼面布局的老方案
I know he mentioned how it reminded him of Tintin's rocket many times,
他说过很多次 这让他想起了 丁丁历险记 里的火箭
and considering how much he loves aesthetics,
考虑到他也很喜欢外观美
this might actually be kind of true.
这有可能是真的
- I think it looks beautiful.
- 我认为它看上去很美
And I love the Tintin rocket design,
我喜欢 丁丁历险记里 的火箭设计
so I kind of wanted to bias it towards that.
让我比较想去实现它
- And I'm a little torn up on this one actually,
- 我对此比较不以为然
because I thought it was super cool that the landing legs were also the control surfaces.
(尽管)因为着陆腿也是操控舵面这一点感觉很厉害
But then again, there was that third leg that didn't articulate at all
但是第三条腿的作用是什么 还是搞不清楚
and would've had a lot of additional dead weight,
而且这会带来很多额外的质量
and not to mention,
更别说
making your control surfaces also handle the weight
让你的控制面承载这种重量
and impacted the entire ship would've likely been rather difficult to engineer.
导致整艘船很可能更难设计
Now, I'm not saying it couldn't be done in the future
我现在不是说以后做不出来
and it might not be something that they update to later on,
也不是说以后他们不会朝这个方向升级
but for now, the easiest path forward for these first prototypes,
但就目前而言 原型要尽可能容易地造出来
if they separate the landing legs from the fins,
如果他们把支腿从后方翼面上分离出来
it might have simplified things quite a bit.
事情也许会简化不少
Not to mention, say you had a rough landing on Mars and broke a landing gear,
更何况 假设你在火星上着陆得很粗暴 搞坏了起落架
at least it's not integrated into your primary control surface
这个起落架至少没有集成到主要控制面上
that helps you survive re-entering Earth's atmosphere.
而控制面可以帮你顺利再入地球大气
I mean, that's unlikely, but having the two systems separate might not be a bad thing,
虽然说(利用到冗余性的)情况不多 但是把两个系统分开并不是坏事
especially as they develop the vehicle.
特别是这个航天器还在开发中
And after all, don't forget, these first prototypes are really just technology demonstrators.
还有别忘了 这毕竟只是一个用来技术验证的原型机
They're flying science experiments that are built as inexpensively and quickly as possible,
它们会被用来廉价快速地进行飞行科学实验
to start shaking out some of these new technologies.
从而开始搞清楚一些新技术
Nothing on Starship is set in stone.
Starship总在变
I mean, look at how much the Falcon 9 evolved in such a short timeframe.
看看猎鹰9号在这么短时间内发生的变化
Starship is taking that concept up another notch.
Starship只不过是这个概念在另一个领域的实现
So, if the easiest path forward for now is landing legs on the body and the flaps separate,
所以 如果现在最简单的演进途径是着陆腿放在机身上 和襟翼分开
sweet, yeah, get it going.
这么做好 那就这么做
At last year's Dear Moon event,
在去年的 亲爱的月球 大会上
it stood out to me that Elon said a few times
很显然地是 马一龙说了好几次
how the third leg is only a leg and it's not a rear stabilizer of any kind,
第三条腿只是一条腿而非任何形式的稳定装置
and mostly because on re-entry that fin is entirely in the wake of the vehicle
因为在再入大气的时候 那条后方翼面一直呆在飞船后面
and it doesn't even touch the airstream.
根本没碰到气流
Later on, if it does prove to actually be lighter to integrate the landing legs onto the flaps,
如果后来证明了把着陆腿放到襟翼上会更轻
nothing's going to stop SpaceX from evolving Starship to do exactly that.
那么SpaceX也肯定会把Starship做成那样
But in the meantime, I actually think
与此同时 我真的认为
that the aerodynamics team at SpaceX
SpaceX的空气动力学团队
was likely begging engineering to reconsider three fins for a few reasons.
可能真的由于一些事情请求过对这个三后方翼面进行重新设计
Now, here's where we're going to get into speculation land for a little second,
让我推测一下
but I've always been questioning how three would've worked,
我一直对三个后方翼面的方案很质疑
because of some basic physics.
因为一些基本的物理学
About exactly your ago I did a video about the belly-flop maneuver,
差不多一年前我做了一个肚皮翻滚机动的视频
and in order to help me get it to work well I had to keep the fins tucked in on ascent,
为了让它工作 我不得不在上升段把它的后方翼面收起来
and I needed to keep them behind the center of mass on descent.
然后让它们在下降段时保持在质心后面
Here, let me show you something.
这儿我要跟你讲讲
The general rule of thumb for anything flying is,
对于飞行器的普遍规则是
you want your center of pressure or lift behind your center of mass.
你的压力或者升力中心在你的质心后面
Otherwise, if the vehicle moves away from its heading at all,
否则 一旦航天器偏离它的指向
the surfaces will induce lift or torque on the vehicle,
表面会对航天器产生升力或者扭矩
and since it's in front, it'll become a feedback loop.
而且因为它是在前面 所以会产生一个反馈回路
(这些线展示了气动力的强度和方向)
Say it pulls up just a little,
假设只是拉起一点点
that's going to change the angle of attack on the surface,
就会改变表面的攻角
which will make it pitch up a little more,
就会让其仰角多一点
which will change the angle of attack on the surface,
就会改变表面的攻角
which will make it want to pull up a little more,
就会多拉起一点
which will change the angle of attack on the surface,
就会改变表面的攻角
which will make it wanna, et cetera, et cetera,
等等
until you lose control,
直到你失去了控制
and that surface will want to flip around to the back where it belongs.
而表面就会翻转到背面去
That's because, in the back,
这是因为 在背面
those forces actually do the exact opposite thing and work to stability's advantage.
这些力在做完全相反的事情 同时增强稳定性
When a craft starts to pitch away from its heading,
当飞船开始偏离其指向
the fins apply torque to recenter the craft.
翼面会产生回位的力矩
The further away from your heading you pitch the more torque it applies,
你偏离得越多 这种力矩就施加得越大
which makes it very inherently stable.
使其本身很稳定
This principle applies to Starship during three different phases, ascent, re-entry and landing,
这一原则适用于Starship的三个不同的阶段 上升 再入和着陆段
and it does so in three very different ways.
并且以三种不同的方式实现
That's why,
这就是为什么
when we started seeing renderings and animations of the three-fin Starship
当我们开始看到三后方翼面Starship的渲染动画时
ascending on the super-heavy booster,
上升段搭载在超重助推器上面
my eyes got a little wide and I got a little worried.
我有点担心地瞪大了眼睛
When I saw that, I thought about throwing a dart backwards.
我看到时 就想到猛地往后倒飞
It's probably not gonna fly backwards very long,
它很可能不会倒飞很长时间
it's probably gonna flip right over and orient itself so the fins are in the back.
它很可能会翻转过来 然后指向一个翼面都在背面的方向
Now, that's not to say it can't be done,
现在 这并不是说不能这样做
because the engines have an awful lot of control authority with their gimbal,
因为发动机的平衡环架(矢量)有很大的控制能力
and they can help maintain proper orientation.
它们可以帮助保持正确的方向
But in general, it's much, much more difficult to fly
但总地来说 还是难飞多了
with large aero surfaces that far out in front of your center of mass.
那么多气动表面都在你的质心前面
Luckily, computers are really good at managing crazy aerodynamic properties,
幸运地是 计算机擅长控制这些疯狂的空气动力学特性
which is why all modern fighter jets are inherently unstable and are fly-by-wire,
这就是为什么所有的现代战斗机本身是不稳定的 是电传操纵的
where computer actually interprets the input from the pilot
电传操纵中 计算机解释了飞行员的输入
and moves whatever surfaces necessary to move the aircraft as the pilot intended.
按需移动飞行员想要移动的空气动力学表面
(upbeat music)
(欢快的音乐)
Okay, so why would two be better than three on ascent?
那么 为什么上升段时两个比三个更好？
Won't two still be an issue?
难道两个就不是问题了？
Besides the fact that there's less fins in the first place,
除了翼面越少越好这个因素以外
there's something two can do that three can't really do easily,
三个比两个更难的情况
and that's get tucked in away from the airstream.
就是你可以收紧它们 躲避气流的影响
While on ascent, a pair of fins can easily tuck in against their airframe
在上升段时 一对翼面可以很容易地紧贴到机身上
and mostly negate their aerodynamic properties.
尽最大程度地消除它们的空气动力学性质
Both the top and bottom fins will do this.
顶部和底部的翼面都能做到
Whereas three fins, especially when one was an immobile landing leg only,
而三个翼面 特别是其中一个只是固定的着陆腿的时候
can't really tuck in out of the airstream entirely.
真的没法完全避免气流的影响
I mean, sure, they could've tucked two in and left the third one out
没错 是可以只收两个 让第三个晾外边
and kept that more in the wake of the vehicle during its gravity turn,
让它在航天器重力转弯时的背面
but it's still just not the most stable configuration.
但这仍然不是最稳定的配置
Okay, but forget ascent.
好吧 不谈上升段了
I'm sure they can do that no problem either way if they had to.
如果他们必须做 无论以哪种方式 肯定都能做
The bigger challenge is actually with the descent of Starship, with three versus two fins.
三翼面相比两翼面 在下降段遇到的挑战更大
And again, this has everything to do with tucking the fins in.
这些都与收紧翼面有关
Let's actually watch the real physics simulation
让我们看看真正的物理模拟
that Elon showed at last year's Dear Moon presentation.
马一龙去年在 亲爱的月球 演讲中展示的那样
You'll see the vehicle does the belly-first to tail-down flip at only about 1.5 kilometers in altitude,
你会发现航天器的水平到垂直姿态的变换发生在仅仅1.5km的高空
while still traveling at mach one for landing on Mars.
对于火星着陆而言 速度则高达1倍音速
Now notice, during this landing phase,
现在注意 在着陆阶段
the rear fins are tucked in all the way until the very last second.
后方翼面一直处在收起状态 直到降落前的最后时刻
But even so, the vehicle has one giant fin fully eating the wind stream in front of the vehicle.
但即便如此 这个航天器仍有一个巨大的后方翼面在完全吃进航天器前方的气流
Any movement away from the vehicle's heading will induce a lot of torque.
任何偏离航天器指向的移动都会引入很大的力矩
And again, the gimbals on the Raptors
同样 在猛禽发动机上的平衡环架(矢量)
and the attitude control thrusters can offset all of this torque
和姿态控制推进器可以抵消这一切的扭矩
and hopefully maintain stability,
并且很有希望能保持稳定
but if you have the option of eliminating something that's going to actively try and make your vehicle lose control,
但如果你能在这之前就把这种让航天器失控的因素消除
it might not be a bad idea to change it.
消除它总是好的
And Elon did go on to say,
马一龙当时也说了
"Stability is controlled by very rapid movement of rear and forward fins during entry and landing,"
稳定性是靠后方和前方翼面的非常快的运动来控制的
"as well as ACS thrusters," or attitude control thrusters.
以及ACS推进器 或说姿态控制推进器
"The smaller leeward fin would simply be used as a leg."
较小的背风的翼面将只被当作腿来使用
But I think he's mainly talking about re-entry,
但我觉得他只说了再入段
because during the actual landing portion,
因为实际上 在着陆的这一段
the legs and upper fins can only articulate on their dihedral axis.
腿和前方翼面只能按机翼上下反角轴向运动
Now, if these fins had the ability to also act like canards,
那么 如果这些这些翼面能像鸭翼那样动
which would be able to produce two axes of control through the x-axis of the rocket,
这将能够通过火箭的x轴 以产生控制另外两轴的力
I can see where the statement would be true.
我才能认为这个观点是对的
But during the final tail-down landing portion,
但在最后的尾部朝下降落的那部分
they are essentially passive.
它们本质上是被动的
Notice, with just the two fins on the bottom,
请注意 只有在底部的两个翼面
again, just like on ascent,
就像和在上升段的事情一样
we can tuck them in against the fuselage and mostly negate their aerodynamic effects.
可以把他们紧紧贴在机身上来抵消它们的空气动力学效应
Not to mention, there aren't any portion of these new fins that are sticking out below the engines,
更不用说 这些新的翼面没有任何部分突出在发动机下方
which would put them in front of the airstream of the vehicle as it descends,
而这些部分会导致他们在下降段 处在比机身更前方的位置接触气流
which again is a bad thing.
这又是一件坏事
The other problem with the three landing legs is a little more complicated,
三个着陆腿的另一个问题是 有点更复杂
but I'll bet the aerodynamics team had a pretty great time
但我打赌空气动力学团队肯定要度过一段难忘的时光
going over the properties of the three-legged re-entry.
在考虑三条着陆腿再入性能的时候
When re-entering, the vehicle will be completely belly-flopping, and that is,
再入的时候 航天器将完全是机腹朝下的状态 那就是
coming in broadside with its belly facing the airstream.
用侧面 用它的腹部来朝向气流
Well, hold on actually.
等下
It'll mostly belly-flop.
主要是机腹朝下
But it sounds like, according to Elon Musk,
但根据马一龙的说法
"It does actually generate lift in hypersonic regime,"
它在高超音速段确实产生升力
"which is important to limit peak heating."
对于减少热量而言至关重要
In other words, it could probably pitch down a little bit,
换句话说 它的机头很可能稍微向下一点
which would allow the body to create a little additional lift,
这样可以让机身创造一点点额外的升力
which can also limit peak heating and make sure it doesn't ever get too hot.
这也可以限制热量的峰值 并确保它不会太热
With three legs, they're attached at a 120 degrees apart from each other,
而三条腿的情况 它们以120度角分开
which puts the two fins that articulate awfully close to the center of mass of the rocket.
这使得转动的那两个翼面离火箭的质心非常近
Now, this isn't necessarily a bad thing.
这未必是一件坏事
In fact, a traditional capsule shape intentionally has
事实上 传统的胶囊形状 是有意
a center of pressure in front of the center of mass.
让压力处在质心的前面
This is known as blunt body dynamics,
这被称为钝体空气动力学
and in 1952, H. Julian Allen of NACA,
并且在1952年 美国国家航空咨询委员会的H·朱利安·艾伦
now NASA's Ames Aeronautical Lab,
也就是现在NASA的艾姆斯航空实验室
discovered a capsule was most stable and dissipated the most heat
发现胶囊外形是最稳定的 而且消耗的热量最多
when it had a blunt surface facing the wind stream.
当他的迎风面是钝面的时候
So, perhaps the fins could function in this manner,
所以 也许翼面能在这种情况下起作用
but considering how much they actually need to move throughout re-entry,
但是考虑到它们在再入的时候需要移动
I could see it again being less stable than having those fins behind the center of mass.
我还是觉得它们不如把翼面放在质心后面的方式稳定
I even wonder if they do end up going with integrating the legs back onto the fins someday,
我甚至觉得 如果有一天要把着陆腿整合回去
if they'll have a retractable third leg that would be in the front of the vehicle,
航天器的前面会有一个可伸缩的第三条腿
so facing windward,
那么 迎风的那一面
and let the other two fins remain behind the center of mass for better passive stability.
会让两外两个翼面保持在重心后面 这样会有更好的被动稳定性
So this is another time we're having just two fins,
这是另外一种 只有两个翼面
when partially retracted through the re-entry,
在再入时部分收起
would have a better, more passively stable configuration.
将有一个更好 更稳定的被动配置
But again, I'm sure they really cool ways to deal with some of these things.
但同样 我敢肯定 他们会有一些很好的方法来处理这些事情
But I'm thinking they actually made
但我觉得他们真的
a significantly more stable vehicle by only having two fins in the rear.
做过一个更稳定的 只有两个后方翼面的航天器
If we see them tucked in on ascent and tucked in on landing,
如果我们在上升段和着陆段看到它们收起来了
that kind of proves that this is indeed advantageous.
这就证明实际上(两个翼面的设计)是有利的
Okay, so that's a quick overview of why I think two is better than three.
好吧 这就是我认为两个比三个好的概论
So let's have some fun,
那么 让我们开心点儿
and I'm gonna show you just
而我会告诉你
how exactly you can control all three axes of control with just two upper fins and two lower fins.
只通过两个前方翼面和两个后方翼面来控制飞行器的三个轴向
Now, this method of control hasn't actually changed at all,
现在 这种控制方法实际上并没有根本改变
because that third fin on the back was really completely passive and out of the wind stream,
因为背面的第三个翼面是完全被动 不经过气流的
so everything we talk about here is the same way it would've worked with three fins in the back too.
所以我们这里所讲的和三个翼面(其中有一个)在后面是一样的
It's actually a really cool method of control,
这种控制方法其实很厉害
I've never really seen anything like this.
我之前从未见过类似的东西
Remember, these flaps are perpendicular to the wind stream
请记住 这些翼面垂直于气流
and not parallel like the wings or ailerons of an airplane.
和飞机的机翼或副翼 那样平行于气流不同
The only thing we can do is increase or decrease the amount of drag each one produces.
我们所能做的只是增加或减少每个翼面产生的阻力
Remember, a plane typically uses a change in lift or deflection to induce pitch, yaw, and roll.
请记住 一般情况下飞机通过升力和偏转力的变化来控制俯仰 偏航和滚转
Starship will essentially use drag brakes to control its pitch, yaw and roll,
Starship将主要使用气动阻力板来控制俯仰 偏航和滚转
and most aircraft do not do this.
与大多数飞机不同
My favorite example of this is the B-2 Stealth Bomber,
我最喜欢的例子是B-2隐形轰炸机
which doesn't have a tail stabilizer.
它没有(垂直)尾翼
So, in order to induce yaw,
为了引入偏航轴
it actually opens up what's called a split aileron,
它发展出一种分裂副翼
which can induce drag on one wing or the other,
可以在一侧的机翼上引入阻力
which then controls the jet's yaw.
就可以控制其偏航
Here's how this works.
这是它工作的原理
Now, we're still gonna consider the cockpit our frame of reference for pitch, yaw, and roll.
现在 我们还是按照座舱视角的参考系考虑俯仰 偏航和滚转
To induce pitch, the top and bottom fins can move opposite each other.
为了引入俯仰 顶部和底部的翼面可以朝相反方向移动
One extends more while the other retracts,
一对伸展一对收回
which can help pitch the nose up or push it down.
它可以把机头抬起或按下
To induce roll, the left and right flaps can move opposite each other.
为了引入滚转 左右的翼面可以朝相反方向移动
Extend one side more than the other and the vehicle will roll.
一边伸展一边收回 就能滚转
But you can even induce yaw.
你甚至能引入偏航
For this, we move opposite corners of each other.
只要让翼面按对角相同 左右相反的方式运动即可
Top left and bottom right can move opposite of the top right and bottom left.
左上和右下可以与右上和左下进行相反的运动
This will induce yaw as it belly-flops through the atmosphere.
使用这种方式 它就能在机腹向下 通过大气的时候进行偏航操作
And this is exactly why Elon keeps saying this vehicle is more like a skydiver than an airplane.
而这也正是马一龙所说的 这个航天器 相比飞机更像是跳伞运动
A skydiver needs to use their limbs to control themselves in a very similar manner,
跳伞者需要通过肢体来实现对他们身体类似的控制
something I once found out I'm awful at.
我发现那是我完全不擅长的事情
素材出处：www.facebook.com/738102993243948/videos/754291784958402
It's a lot harder than it looks.
这比它看起来难多了
Every tiny bit of movement I make creates a lot of torque,
我做的任何一点运动都带来了大量扭矩
thanks to the grids on my grid fin.
得益于我拿着的栅格翼上的栅格
So, throughout re-entry,
所以在整个再入过程中
the computer will be continually adjusting the flaps to maintain orientation and a stable configuration,
计算机将不停地调节翼面来保持机头指向和稳定的配置
but they can also adjust their total drag coefficiency
但计算机也可以调整航天器的总阻力系数
to help perfectly nail their downrange distance.
来精确控制弹道下方的距离
And don't forget, the vehicle can also use attitude control thrusters throughout re-entry.
而且别忘了 航天器也可以在再入段使用姿态控制推进器
But with that being a limited quantity,
但用量是有限的
the more work the flaps can do the better.
襟翼能做的工作越多越好
Now, it's gonna maintain this orientation as long as it can,
他得尽可能地保持着这个指向
because that belly-flop does an awesome job of slowing it down without using any propellant,
因为机腹朝下的方式确实能很好地减速下来而不需要任何推进剂
so they really wanna do that flip as late as possible.
所以这里需要做的是尽可能地迟些翻转
After all, as soon as it goes tail down,
毕竟 只要它机尾朝下了
it's actually a lot more aerodynamic and will fall a lot quicker,
它的气动更好 (空气阻力更小) 下降得更快
so the engines actually have a lot more work to do.
所以发动机就需要做很多事情了
Once the vehicle's ready to do its flip,
一旦航天器准备好做翻转
they're going to tuck the rear fins in and extend the upper ones.
后方翼面将收起 前方翼面将伸展开
Then they'll light up three of its Raptor engines,
然后启动三台猛禽发动机
and alongside with the ACS,
以及ACS发动机
they're going to reorient the rocket so it basically ends up landing kind of like a Falcon 9.
让火箭重新指向 最终像猎鹰9号一样着陆
(uplifting music)
(令人振奋的音乐)
And then, when the timing is just right,
然后 当时机恰到好处
they're going to extend those landing legs,
就伸出这些着陆腿
throttle the engines just perfectly and hopefully make a perfect, perfect touchdown.
完美地节流发动机 并期待着进行一次完美地着陆
Yes, there we go.
没错 就这样
Okay, that's the one.
就是这个
(laughing) Yes!
(笑)是的
That's what I'm talkin' about, right there. Holy cow.
这就是我所说的(完美着陆)
Now, that will be something to see.
这就很让人期待了
I mean, come on, I can't help but laugh about how ho-hum Falcon 9 landings have become already.
得了吧 对于猎鹰9号的着陆变得枯燥这件事总是让我忍俊不禁
God, we really do have the attention span of a bunch of five-year-olds, don't we?
我们确实只有着5岁小孩一样的注意力范围
And in case you're wondering,
如果你想知道这是怎么做到的
kerbalx.com/EverydayAstronaut/StarShip-2019
raw.githubusercontent.com/Bourshevik0/Everyday-Astronaut-KSP-crafts/master/StarShip%202019.craft
yes, I do have the craft file link in the description.
是的 简介里确实有飞行器设计文件
It's all stock, but it does utilize Kerbal Breaking Ground DLC for those robotics.
都是原装组件 但是机械控制使用了坎巴拉Breaking Ground DLC
So, to summarize,
那么 总结下
I truly don't think aerodynamic considerations was the primary reason we're now seeing two fins on Starship,
我真的不认为空气动力学的考虑是Starship现在有两个翼面的主要原因
but I can't help but think it's inherently more stable now.
但我总觉得它现在更稳定了
And when dealing with something that's as big as a skyscraper falling out of the sky
而对于这样像从天而降的摩天大楼一样大的尺寸
with hundreds of tons of explosive propellant on board,
以及装载着数百吨爆炸性的燃料
it's probably a good idea to have physics on your side.
也许有着物理学的支持会更好
It sounds like the primary reason is weight and simplicity.
首要原因大概是(节省)重量和(结构)简单
And just again a friendly reminder,
让我再温馨提示一下
I don't think I know better than anyone on the subject matter.
我认为肯定有别人比我更了解这件事
I'm literally the last person you wanna have working on your spaceship.
如果你要搞飞船设计工作 千万别找我 我不行
But teaching some of these fun principles and applying them to new designs is super fun.
但是讲解这些原理 并且把它们应用到新的设计上真的很有趣
And knowing just how much Elon Musk cares for aesthetics,
而且了解到马一龙是有多在意外观美
I still think his love for the retro styling was a big factor in having three fins,
我仍然认为是他对复古风格的喜好才使用的三翼面设计
because quite frankly, it did look really cool.
坦率地说 这确实看起来很帅
But what do you think?
但你怎么看？
Do you like the two fin version, or are you gonna miss the old retro-throwback three fin version?
你喜欢两翼面版本 还是更怀念之前复古的三翼面版本？
Do you think they'll stick with the two fin for a while,
你觉得他们会坚持用两翼面一段时间
or do you think we'll see them go back to three after these Mark 1 and Mark 2 prototypes?
或者在原型一号机和二号机之后再看到他们用回三翼面设计吗
Do you think they'll tuck in on ascent and portions of descent as well?
你觉得翼面会在上升段和下降段都收起来吗
Let me know what you think and let me know if you have any other questions about re-entry,
请提出你的问题 关于再入
landing burn, Raptor engine, Starship,
着陆点火 猛禽发动机 Starship
or just rockets in general, in the comments below.
或者只是普遍的火箭问题 请在评论区留言
And be sure and stick around,
而且请留意下
because not only am I going down to Boca Chica for the Starship presentation,
因为我不仅要去到博卡奇卡的Starship报告会
@给虫Official 已经搬了逃逸系统这期BV1z7411q7GJ
I'm also going to do a video about why Starship doesn't have an abort system.
我还打算做一个为什么Starship没有逃逸系统的视频
And of course,
而且当然
@长五遥三没有鸽 (他挺忙的，还是别催更了233333)
以及 @给虫Official 做过一些短片段的翻译 BV1XJ411372P
I'll hopefully have my long long long video about aerospike engines done soon as well.
我希望尽快完成关于气尖引擎的长——长——长视频
I promise, it's coming along great,
我保证 视频质量很好
and hopefully, you learn as much as I did making it.
而且希望 你能学到和我制作一样多的知识
I of course also a huge thank you to my Patreon supporters for helping me make all content possible,
including traveling around all the time,
trying to get as much content out there for you guys as I can.
It's been a crazy time lately and you guys are definitely helping me stay sane.
If you wanna join our exclusive subreddit,
our exclusive Discord or gain access to exclusive live streams,
or even give your input to scripts and catch errors on videos before they come out,
please consider becoming a Patreon member by going to patreon.com/EverydayAstronaut.
Thank you.
And while you're online, be sure and check out my web store,
which is getting way cooler every single day.
Seriously, you have to check it out.
We have lots of awesome stuff.
And if you see something in there,
you better get it while it's in there because we do runs of shirts now.
So, that means the quality can go up,
we can do custom things like have tags and lots of other cool things.
So if you see something, grab it while it's in stock,
otherwise it might not be coming back and it might be too late.
And don't forget, if you work in the aerospace industry,
you can click on the link in the description of any apparel item,
and you can actually take 25% off
as my thank you to you for doing awesome things and for helping inspire me to do what I do.
So head on over to EverydayAstronaut.com/shop.
Thanks, everybody. That's gonna do it for me.
I'm Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut,
bringing space down to earth for everyday people.
(upbeat music)
(欢快的音乐)